[{"answer": "Yes, I've always believed, Piers -- the Scripture shows that it's a sin.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 4, "question": "Is homosexuality a sin in your eyes?", "qSentId": 3}, {"answer": "The world we live in is not a perfect world.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 9, "question": "How do you explain a just God can allow this kind of atrocities to happen?", "qSentId": 8}, {"answer": "I'm for second chances and mercy.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 11, "question": "What is your view of state executions?", "qSentId": 10}, {"answer": "My view is that every baby should live.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 14, "question": "If I ask you about abortion, what would you say?", "qSentId": 13}, {"answer": "Well, you know, I think we all can if we -- if we learned what to ignore and -- you know, certain battles not to fight.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 31, "question": "How could you possibly get any happier?", "qSentId": 30}, {"answer": "Well, Piers, for the most people, the studies show that people are happier on Fridays.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 39, "question": "Why have you selected Friday as a day of great joy and happiness?", "qSentId": 38}, {"answer": "I think people are looking for the weekends, looking forward to it, getting to relax, you know, done with work and, you know, I've also read, Piers, where there's more heart attacks on Monday than any other day.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 41, "question": "Why?", "qSentId": 40}, {"answer": "Well, Piers, to me, faith is all about learning to be happy where you are.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 59, "question": "What about the poor guy who's trapped in a factory job or something or maybe has no job who, just through lack of opportunity and bad circumstance, is unhappy because he can't get out of that?", "qSentId": 58}, {"answer": "You know --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 66, "question": "Do you believe, fundamentally, that money can make people happier?", "qSentId": 65}, {"answer": "Well, I mean, it helps -- I mean, it helps but, no, I don't -- I've seen people who are very wealthy and they're unhappy, they don't have good relationships.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 68, "question": "Victoria, you're shaking your head, why?", "qSentId": 67}, {"answer": "I think there's not so many distractions.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 81, "question": "Why can poverty stricken people sometimes find joy in their lives?", "qSentId": 80}, {"answer": "Angry, no.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 89, "question": "Or is he always this content happy chap?", "qSentId": 88}, {"answer": "Never.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 100, "question": "When's the last time you heard him -- when's the last time you heard him shout, Victoria, come on?", "qSentId": 99}, {"answer": "No, he's never shouted --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 102, "question": "You've never heard him shout?", "qSentId": 101}, {"answer": "-- and if you -- listen, if you live with me and you don't shout, you're pretty good.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 104, "question": "He's never shouted?", "qSentId": 103}, {"answer": ".", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 110, "question": "Do you have a temper?", "qSentId": 109}, {"answer": "No, no, that's not my personality.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 118, "question": "Do you never shout at anybody?", "qSentId": 117}, {"answer": "Well, I probably have, you know --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 123, "question": "Let me just clarify, you've never shouted in your life?", "qSentId": 122}, {"answer": "I can't remember.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 125, "question": "When was the last time?", "qSentId": 124}, {"answer": "It's like --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 130, "question": "What's the look?", "qSentId": 129}, {"answer": "You know, I don't know if it would ruin my Friday but I -- like she said, I like things to be right.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 137, "question": "What can ruin your Friday?", "qSentId": 136}, {"answer": "I never have -- I never have.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 143, "question": "Have you ever had a fist fight?", "qSentId": 142}, {"answer": "Well, probably with my brother, yes.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 146, "question": "Not even when you were a kid?", "qSentId": 145}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 153, "question": "Never actually -- have you ever been punched in the face?", "qSentId": 152}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 159, "question": "Have you ever been punched in the face?", "qSentId": 158}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 161, "question": "You have?", "qSentId": 160}, {"answer": "You know, it's difficult, Piers, but the world we live in is not a perfect world.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 179, "question": "How do you explain that a just God can allow this kind of atrocities to happen, ruining so many lives?", "qSentId": 178}, {"answer": "You know, it really --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 186, "question": "Has it ever -- did your faith ever get dented?", "qSentId": 185}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 193, "question": "What do you say to people, again, who might come to you and say, I can't continue having this faith because some appalling thing has happened?", "qSentId": 192}, {"answer": "What I say is this -- God's got you in the palm of his hand.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 201, "question": "What do you say to them?", "qSentId": 200}, {"answer": "I do.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 235, "question": "Do you ever watch yourself back on TV?", "qSentId": 234}, {"answer": "I do still edit them.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 238, "question": "ORGAN: Do you?", "qSentId": 237}, {"answer": "Well, my mother has had a great memory and when I started, you know, my dad just spoke extemporaneously and just would go and I couldn't do that.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 245, "question": "How have you developed that?", "qSentId": 244}, {"answer": "You know, it's a complicated issue, Piers.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 268, "question": "What do you think of the whole issue?", "qSentId": 267}, {"answer": "Well, I don't -- I don't know that that's -- you know, I -- it's -- it's hard for me.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 273, "question": "A life for a life?", "qSentId": 272}, {"answer": "Well, I think the thing is, is we have a justice system and I believe in our system of justice, number one.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 278, "question": "And you've got to have a view, haven't you?", "qSentId": 277}, {"answer": "Well, abortion, I feel stronger about because it -- I feel like --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 301, "question": "If I asked you about abortion, what would you say?", "qSentId": 300}, {"answer": "My view is that every baby should live, that, you know, that God's created that life.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 303, "question": "What's your view?", "qSentId": 302}, {"answer": "Well, I think there could be when you say may or may not.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 307, "question": "Should there not be a more consistent view?", "qSentId": 306}, {"answer": "Yes, I've always believed, Piers, the Scriptures shows that it's a sin.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 323, "question": "Is homosexuality a sin, in your eyes?", "qSentId": 322}, {"answer": "You know, Piers, it really never changes because mine was -- mine's based out of the Scripture.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 331, "question": "What's your view now?", "qSentId": 330}, {"answer": "Sure.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 340, "question": "I mean, like everything else, doesn't it have to move with the times and isn't it down again to people like you to interpret it in a way that evolves when you're known as a very progressive preacher?", "qSentId": 339}, {"answer": "Well, you know what, I'm going to respect the law and I'm going to respect gay people like I do now, you know, I have plenty of people that come to our church and friends, I would call, that are gay so I'm going to respect that.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 346, "question": "What if Texas eventually, in a moment, it's an unlikely place I would imagine to bring this in, but it may change with enough pressure, Texas brings in a law that same-sex marriage is permissible -- how would you feel then if it's the law of the land?", "qSentId": 345}, {"answer": "No, it would be against what I believe the scripture teaches and, so, that's where I think the rub comes in with people like myself.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 349, "question": "You could never do that?", "qSentId": 348}, {"answer": "Well, I think if it was that easy, that we would have figured it out by now.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 358, "question": "I mean, could you ever imagine attending a gay marriage between two people who come to your church, for example, if they invited you?", "qSentId": 357}, {"answer": ".", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 362, "question": "So, would you accept one or not?", "qSentId": 361}, {"answer": "Two gay people who attend your church invite you to their wedding.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 364, "question": "OSTEEN: Would I accept one?", "qSentId": 363}, {"answer": "Well, I don't -- you know, if I had time I would.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 367, "question": "You would?", "qSentId": 366}, {"answer": "If they were friends of mine --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 369, "question": "Joel, would you go?", "qSentId": 368}, {"answer": "Well, I would not --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 376, "question": "Could you be seen to do -- could you be photographed at such an event?", "qSentId": 375}, {"answer": "Piers, they all look like great leaders to me.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 391, "question": "But of all the Republican runners and riders in the race so far to be the nominee, who do you think is the most impressive leader potentially that you've seen?", "qSentId": 390}, {"answer": "But, I'm -- I'm conservative, you know, that's who I've always been.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 408, "question": "Really?", "qSentId": 407}, {"answer": "I like to vote on the candidate.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 412, "question": "You would say?", "qSentId": 411}, {"answer": "Good thing I don't have to right now because it's too early in the race.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 419, "question": "ORGAN: -- who would it be?", "qSentId": 418}, {"answer": "I like Rick Perry.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 422, "question": "Is he the kind of guy?", "qSentId": 421}, {"answer": "Anything.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 430, "question": "I think -- are you talking about political issues?", "qSentId": 429}, {"answer": "They care about their relationships -- their relationships, their finances, and their health.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 433, "question": "When people come to your church, what are -- what's really concerning them?", "qSentId": 432}, {"answer": "Yes, I think they're squabbling too much.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 436, "question": "Do you think politicians, today, are doing the right kind of thing, or are they too busy scuffling with each other in Washington to understand clearly, as you've just defined it, what the real issues are for people in America?", "qSentId": 435}, {"answer": "Yes, I think they're squabbling too much.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 438, "question": "Yes?", "qSentId": 437}, {"answer": "Well, I think, like most Americans, I would hope that they would work together and, you know, what I -- what I see that's difficult these days is any kind of compromise and, you know, it's hard to get 100 percent of what you want.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 443, "question": "When you see them all ranting and raving and being deliberately obstructive to getting things done, what do you think?", "qSentId": 442}, {"answer": "You know what, I'm comfortable with -- that would not stop me from voting for somebody.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 449, "question": "Would you be comfortable with that?", "qSentId": 448}, {"answer": "I don't know a lot about it and here I go again but I don't know a lot --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 454, "question": "Are there aspects to Mormonism which you find offensive?", "qSentId": 453}, {"answer": "-- I don't know a lot about it.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 456, "question": "How can you keep saying that?", "qSentId": 455}, {"answer": "I don't know -- I don't --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 464, "question": "Like what?", "qSentId": 463}, {"answer": "You know what, I don't know enough about their -- their beliefs to -- to point out what they are, to articulate it well.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 470, "question": "Well, what are the things about Mormonism which are awkward for you?", "qSentId": 469}, {"answer": "Sure, I could vote for a Jewish candidate.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 474, "question": "Could you vote for a Jewish candidate?", "qSentId": 473}, {"answer": "Well, I think -- I think I could.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 479, "question": "Could you vote for a Muslim candidate?", "qSentId": 478}, {"answer": "Well, it's a -- it's a difficult situation.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 483, "question": "What do you make of what's going on with the Palestinians and the Israelis right now?", "qSentId": 482}, {"answer": "We did.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 489, "question": "You've both been out there recently I think, to Israel, right?", "qSentId": 488}, {"answer": "We found it very peaceful.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 493, "question": "How did you find it?", "qSentId": 492}, {"answer": "Well, I don't --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 503, "question": "Does it worry you that so many areas of conflict of the world are religion prompted?", "qSentId": 502}, {"answer": "Amen.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 515, "question": "If you receive it, can you say amen tonight?", "qSentId": 514}, {"answer": "I do.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 527, "question": "Do you stop to think, wow, how did this happen?", "qSentId": 526}, {"answer": "That's correct.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 537, "question": "Am I right to think that the church takes in $18 million a year, but all of that gets plowed back in to the church, is that right?", "qSentId": 536}, {"answer": "Well, we give.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 539, "question": "The books that sell by the squillion, you keep all the cash?", "qSentId": 538}, {"answer": "Sure.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 542, "question": "ORGAN: You take some as well?", "qSentId": 541}, {"answer": "We do.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 544, "question": "Take some of it?", "qSentId": 543}, {"answer": "Well, we don't have any problem -- I don't think God has any problem with you being blessed.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 550, "question": "I mean, you're like multimillionaires, aren't you?", "qSentId": 549}, {"answer": "Oh, I like being able to help others.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 556, "question": "You like being rich?", "qSentId": 555}, {"answer": "Sure.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 563, "question": "You give to people to come to you for help?", "qSentId": 562}, {"answer": "You know, Piers, again, it's so far out of my league.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 572, "question": "Would you happily write more money to the treasury?", "qSentId": 571}, {"answer": "Well, I wouldn't be foolish.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 575, "question": "Not you personally, but do you mind paying more tax?", "qSentId": 574}, {"answer": "No, I would -- let them have all of the money and the government run great without the money and I give it away to other people.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 581, "question": "What I was saying was: would you like it?", "qSentId": 580}, {"answer": "Well, you know, I think they pay a good pay a good amount of tax right now as it is.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 585, "question": "What do you think ideologically -- and I ask you, Victoria -- of the principle of rich people paying more tax generally?", "qSentId": 584}, {"answer": "You know, I don't know.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 589, "question": "Isn't it just a convenient thing that rich people come out with?", "qSentId": 588}, {"answer": "I wouldn't mind paying more tax.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 594, "question": "I think that you know, just like you, you know, do you want to pay more taxes?", "qSentId": 593}, {"answer": "I think it is.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 604, "question": "It's a different class structure, isn't it?", "qSentId": 603}, {"answer": "Oh, I'd be thrilled, you know, nothing greater than for your children to follow in your legacy.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 628, "question": "Would you be happy with that?", "qSentId": 627}, {"answer": "Oh, you know what, I never feel like it like that.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 635, "question": "I mean, are you going to have to keep an extra close eye because you're the Osteens, everyone be looking to trip them up?", "qSentId": 634}, {"answer": "Oh, well, we -- we have good conversations.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 657, "question": "What's he talking about?", "qSentId": 656}, {"answer": "Well, we like to have a good dinner and we like to either ride our bikes or we like to just hang out and talk or, you know, we may have a few friends over.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 664, "question": "What's your perfect Friday?", "qSentId": 663}, {"answer": "And I respect him even more.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 669, "question": "What's the secret?", "qSentId": 668}, {"answer": "Well, I think he's a man of what he -- of his word, I think he's a man of what his word.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 671, "question": "Yes, what's the secret of the Joel Osteen magic, you think?", "qSentId": 670}, {"answer": "Oh, that and more.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 676, "question": "Do you agree with all that Joel?", "qSentId": 675}, {"answer": "Oh, I have some kind people -- I don't call them groupies -- but people that, you know, they feel like you've helped them and you know what, I -- listen --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 681, "question": "I mean, you must get some groupies, any?", "qSentId": 680}, {"answer": "I don't -- I don't --", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 684, "question": "Do you get all that?", "qSentId": 683}, {"answer": "I don't -- no, not in the work we do.", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 686, "question": "Are you like popular like Tom Jones, you know?", "qSentId": 685}, {"answer": "Well, I -- you know, it's funny because when I -- when I'm out, even by myself, this is what women say to me, \"Oh, Victoria, I love your husband.\"", "docId": "111008pmt", "aSentId": 690, "question": "Ever do that?", "qSentId": 689}]